ABHIMANYU

I T ASSISTANT @Bihar Prashashnik Sudhar Mission(govt. of Bihar) Siwan,Bihar, India, abhimanyu.camps@gmail.com,+91-7004015490

SUMMARY

Software Engineer, who can bring a diverse skill set and creative drive to software application development.

Offering 4 years of experience in software engineering, analysis and development of software applications using Client-Server Technology using JAVA/J2EEand the technology as mentioned below in the expertise section.

Play a vital role in the entire Software Development Life Cycle from the Systems study through deployment, including Requirements gathering and Analysis, Design, Development, Deployment, Maintenance, and enhancements of business applications.

Specialized in thinking outside the box to find the unique solution for difficult engineering problems and having ability to work independently

EXPERTISE

Languages : Java (1.8)
Web Technology : JSP, Servlet 2.0

Frame Work : Spring (IOC, JdbcTemplate, DAO, MVC), Java Script.

Databases : MySQL, Oracle App Servers / Web Servers : : Apache Tomcat 9

Operating Systems : Windows Family, Linux, Unix

Project Maven : Maven,

Tools : Git,Postman, Eclipse, photoshop

CERTIFICATIONS

Web Based Application Development Using JEE at Ardent FinishingSchool, Salt Lake Kolkata

EXPERIENCES

I T ASSISTANT Dec 2017 – Till Date

Bihar Prashashnik Sudhar Mission(Govt Of Bihar)

Supervisor Mar 2014 –Nov 2017

Pradhan mantra awaas yoina

(Rural development department, Govt Of Bihar)

PROJECTS

Service Plus (https://serviceonline.bihar.gov.in)

Application processing for e-services of Bihar

This service is a joint initiative to provide government services within specified time in a transparent and convenient manner through e-service online portal.

The aim of this project is providing Government services to the citizen and Business at their door-steps. The online e-services on service Plus will automate front-end as well as back-end work-flow process of Government to citizen

Social security pension management information centre (https://www.sspmis.bihar.gov.in/):

SSPMIS Software Application, an web-based solution for identification and management of beneficiaries based on future needs and requirements of State Society for Ultra Poor and Social Welfare (SSUPSW) under Department of Social Welfare, Government of Bihar.

Technologies Used:

Data Structure, Java (1.8), Multithreading, JSP, JavaScript, Spring, Git, Maven, Postman Eclipse, etc...

Roles and Responsibility

- Adding the new feature for the newly added solutions.
- Understanding the requirement properly and writing the quality code.
- Participating in the each of the planning meeting for breaking/understanding the requirements.
- Writing application for the product clients, debugging complex issues on diverse platforms which involve in-depth analysis of the product series internal codes.
- Serving as a primary point of contact for critical issues.
- Collaborate with internal teams.
- Review and debug code.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science Engineering 2008–2012

West Bengal University of Technology, Kolkata, India

DECLARATION OF AUTHENTICATION

I have by declared that the above-mentioned information is correct up to my best knowledge and belief and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above-mentioned particulars.

Place: Siwan Abhimanyu